💌 cristianmsbr@gmail.com | 🏕 crhenr.xyz | 🖸 crhenr | 🛅 crhenr | 🐚 crhenr | 🎓 Cristian Souza | Lattes CV

Summary_

Currently studying Computer Systems Networking at IFRN, Brazil. Experienced in information security, system administration, computer vision, and image processing. Works on research projects since high school. Likes trying new tools and technologies, as well as developing new open-source projects to help the community.

Experience _____

INSTRUCTOR

SutHub Remote

Back-end Developer Nov 2020 -

- Developed multiple Robotic Process Automation (RPA) tools.
- Main programming language: Python.
- Other technologies: Selenium, AWS (EC2, CloudWatch, and S3), MySQL.

Daryus Consultoria e Treinamento

Remote

Jan 2021 -

- Taught multiple Web Application Security classes for developers and security professionals.
- Main contents: OWASP Top 10, OWASP Secure Coding Practices, OWASP Proactive Controls, OWASP API Security, SAST, DAST, SCA, DevOps, DevSecOps and Threat modeling.

Actions Security Remote

Information Security Analyst May 2018 - Jul. 2019

- · Main programming languages: Python and C.
- Contributed to the development of a Web Application Firewall (WAF).
- Worked with the Elastic Stack, Docker containers and reverse proxies.
- Implanted an OpenStack infrastructure.
- · Executed penetration tests in web applications.
- Other technologies: OWASP Top 10, AWS, OpenStack, ModSecurity, Linux.

Federal Institute of Rio Grande do Norte

Natal, RN - Brazil

Apr. 2016 - Dec. 2018

- Main programming languages: Java and Python.Worked in the fields of computer vision and image processing.
- Developed an ALPR application for embedded hardware (with patent application).
- Developed an OCR application.

R&D SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Developed a deep learning face recognition application and API.
- Other technologies: OpenCV, dlib, REST, Flask, MySQL, RFID.

Education

IFRN (Federal Institute of Rio Grande do Norte)

Natal, RN - Brazil

COMPUTER SYSTEMS NETWORKING DEGREE

2019 - Now

IMD (Digital Metropolis Institute)

CERTIFICATE PROGRAM IN ELECTRONICS

Natal, RN - Brazil 2018 - 2019

IFRN (Federal Institute of Rio Grande do Norte)

Natal, RN - Brazil

CERTIFICATE PROGRAM IN INFORMATICS

2015 - 2018

Skills ____

Languages Portuguese (native), English (advanced level), French (basic level)

Programming C, Java, Python, Shell Script, SQL

Generic AWS, Penetration Testing, OWASP Top 10, Git, Docker, Elastic Stack, Linux Administration, Flask, REST

March 19, 2021 Cristian Souza · Resume 1

Linux+, CompTIA 9BSTQ4TM5LEE1GKT LPIC-1, Linux Professional Institute LPI000393801 Research Papers On detecting and mitigating phishing attacks through featureless machine learning DOI: 10.1002/itl2.135 techniques WILEY INTERNET TECHNOLOGY LETTERS 2020 · Cristian Henrique M. Souza, Marcilio O. O. Lemos, Felipe S. Dantas Silva, Robinson L. Souza Alves MTD para Proteção de Redes SDN **ENCOM 2020** CONFERÊNCIA NACIONAL EM COMUNICAÇÕES, REDES E SEGURANÇA DA INFORMAÇÃO 2020 · Cristian Henrique M. Souza, Túlio A. Pascoal, Emídio P. Neto, Francisco S. Lima Filho, Felipe S. Dantas Silva PhishKiller: Uma Ferramenta para Detecção e Mitigação de Ataques de Phishing Através SBSeq 2019 de Técnicas de Deep Learning XIX SIMPÓSIO BRASILEIRO DE SEGURANÇA DA INFORMAÇÃO E DE SISTEMAS COMPUTACIONAIS 2019 • Cristian Henrique M. Souza, Marcilio O. O. Lemos, Felipe S. Dantas Silva, Robinson Luis S. Alves **Embedded System for Access Control Based on Facial Biometry and RFID** DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-02683-7_62 PROCEEDINGS OF THE FUTURE TECHNOLOGIES CONFERENCE · Cristian Henrique M. Souza, Ivanilson França V. Júnior, Robinson Luis S. Alves, Arthur Henrique C. Costa, Melquiades P. Lima Júnior **Honors & Awards** CVE-2019-7634, Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures 2019 Capture the Wave Champion, Darkwaves Conference 2018 **Open-source Projects** Freki MALWARE ANALYSIS PLATFORM Python • Features: static analysis, user management, REST API, and Web UI. **OpenBSD self-hosted** DEPLOY PRIVATE SERVICES ON TOP OF OPENBSD Shell Script · Features: automatically installs and configures cloud, git, and email services. **JCEditor** ADVANCED TEXT EDITOR Java • Features: syntax-highlighting, cross-platform, Swing UI. Patents & Software Sistema Embarcado para Reconhecimento Automático de Placas de Veículos 2018 BR 10 2018 015493 1 **NAVI RPi Face Recognition** 2019 BR512019000143-5 **NAVI-ALPR** BR512019000144-3 **NAVI Face Recognition API** BR512019000141-9

Certifications

Sistema Embarcado para Medição de Pluviosidade e Gerenciamento SNMP	2019
BR512019000140-0	

OCR-NAVI 2018

BR512018000086-0